Peter and Rose Krasnow
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Peter and Rose Krasnow papers
1914-1984
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Krasnow, Peter
5.7 linear feet
The papers of painter, printmaker, and sculptor Peter Krasnow (1886-1979) and his wife, writer Rose Krasnow (1885-1984), measure 5.7 linear feet and date from 1914 to 1984. Papers include biographical materials, a sound recording, correspondence, essays, poetry, short stories, notes, transcripts of lectures and radio talks, five diaries of Peter Krasnow, personal business records, exhibition catalogs and announcements, clippings, magazines, five sketchbooks, sketches and drawings in multiple media, prints, and photographs.
Provenance
The Peter and Rose Krasnow papers were donated in several increments between 1976 and 1998 by Peter Krasnow, the Estate of Peter Krasnow, and the Peter and Rose Krasnow Foundation.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Biographical Note
Peter Krasnow (1886-1979) was a painter, sculptor, and printmaker who lived and worked primarily in Southern California. His wife, Rose Krasnow (1885-1984), was a prolific writer of poems, short stories, and plays.
Peter Krasnow was born on August 20, 1886 in the Ukraine, Russia to Jewish parents. His father's work as an interior designer inspired Krasnow's interest in art.
In 1907, Krasnow emigrated to the United States, first living in Boston. He moved to Chicago in 1908 to attend the Art Institute of Chicago, where he met his future wife, Rose Bloom. To support himself during his studies, Krasnow worked as a security officer and performed other manual jobs. He graduated from the Art Institute of Chicago in 1916 and married Rose that same year.
The Krasnows moved to New York in 1919. In New York, Krasnow experienced some artistic success, participating in group and solo exhibitions at the Whitney Studio Club. During this time period, Krasnow often painted city scenes using a dark color palette.
In 1922, the Krasnows moved to Los Angeles, California. Krasnow built a studio near Glendale in 1923, on land purchased from photographer and friend Edward Weston. The studio also served as the Krasnows' main residence for the rest of their lives. In 1923 in Los Angeles, Krasnow exhibited with the Group of Independent Artists, which included Stanton Macdonald-Wright, Boris Deutsch, Nick Brigante, Ben Berlin, and other noteworthy artists. During his first years in California, Krasnow mostly created watercolor paintings, including a series of landscapes, using a lighter color palette than his earlier works. In the 1920s, Krasnow also accepted commissions for carved wood reliefs at the Temple Emmanu-El in San Francisco and the Sinai Temple in Los Angeles.
Krasnow received a grant in 1931, and he and Rose temporarily relocated to the Dordogne region of France, where they lived until 1934. During this time, Krasnow painted a series of watercolors and paintings of the French landscape. Before returning to the United States, Krasnow exhibited these landscapes at the Galerie Pierre.
After returning to California, Krasnow began creating carved wood sculptures, which he named 'demountables,' often using wood from trees on his property. Krasnow created these sculptures to celebrate the organic shapes inherent in wood.
In 1934, Krasnow returned to painting, this time creating bright, colorful, geometric designs which often incorporated symbolism from his Jewish heritage. Krasnow focused on these paintings through the remaining years of his life. In 1977, Krasnow received a fellowship from the National Endowment for the Arts.
Peter Krasnow died on October 30, 1979 in Los Angeles. Rose Krasnow died five years later, in 1984.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of painter, printmaker, and sculptor Peter Krasnow (1886-1979) and his wife, writer Rose Krasnow (1885-1984), measure 5.7 linear feet and date from 1914 to 1984. Papers include biographical materials, a sound recording, correspondence, essays, poetry, short stories, notes, transcripts of lectures and radio talks, five diaries of Peter Krasnow, personal business records, exhibition catalogs and announcements, clippings, magazines, five sketchbooks, sketches and drawings in multiple media, prints, and photographs.
Biographical materials include documentation of Rose Krasnow's service as a member of the Army Air Forces Ground Observer Corps, programs and other materials from various memorial services, a sound recording with commentary on a Peter Krasnow exhibition, and documentation of a project to publish Rose Krasnow's poetry.
Correspondence consists of Peter and Rose Krasnow's personal and professional correspondence as well as a small amount of third party correspondence. Personal correspondence with friends and family involves health, work, daily events, and other life updates. Professional correspondence with art dealers, curators, gallery and museum directors, collectors, and colleges and universities concerns exhibitions, sales, loans, and donations of artwork. Primary correspondents include Leslie Burton and Harriet Blades, Dan Budnik, Grace Clements, Conrad Crocker, Dudley Howe, Lilly Weil Jaffe, Grace L. McCann Morley, Dale and Elaine Owen, Aimée Brown Price, Ernest and Ina Raboff, Irving Stone, and Edward Weston. There are also numerous scattered letters from artists, writers, curators, critics, museums, arts associations, and Jewish organizations.
Writings and notes are by Peter Krasnow, Rose Krasnow, and others. Writings by Peter Krasnow include a draft autobiography, essays, lectures on wood sculpture, typescripts, notes, and writings on art. Writings by Rose Krasnow include essays, plays, poetry, and short stories. Writings by others consist of essays, lectures, notes, plays, poetry, short stories, and typescripts. Other writers include Grace Clements, Fidel Danieli, Robert DeLuce, Alfred S. Drake, and Philip Noer. There are also five handwritten personal diaries by Peter Krasnow.
Personal business records include Rose Krasnow's bank book from 1980, Peter Krasnow's naturalization certificate and passport, an inventory of paintings on index cards, tax applications for the Peter Krasnow Arts Foundation, materials relating to Peter Krasnow's estate and the purchase of his artwork, and various receipts.
Printed materials include exhibition catalogs and announcements, clippings, bound books, magazines and journals, a Chicago Society of Artists block print calendar, and two printed posters from Peter Krasnow's exhibit at the Galerie Pierre in 1934.
Artwork is mostly by Peter Krasnow, and includes five sketchbooks, sketches and drawings, watercolors, preliminary studies in oil, and prints.
Photographs include personal photographs, photographs of major sculpture projects in progress, and artwork. Personal photographs are of Peter and Rose, family members, and friends, as well as a few scattered images of landscapes and architecture, possibly travel photographs. There are also photographs of Edward and Flora Weston. There are three photograph albums, one contains images of Krasnow's relief sculptures for the Sinai Temple's Kohn Chapel. Two photograph albums were compliled by Susan Ehrlich for Peter and Rose Krasnow. Also found are photographs of works of art. Some of the photographs in the papers were taken by Dan Budnik.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 9 series:
Series 1: Biographical Materials, circa 1942-1983 (Boxes 1, 6; 7 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, circa 1930-1984 (Box 1; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 3: Writings and Notes, circa 1916-1980 (Boxes 1-2; 1.3 linear feet)
Series 4: Diaries, circa 1955-1968 (Box 2-3; 5 folders)
Series 5: Personal Business Records, circa 1914-1982 (Box 3; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 6: Printed Materials, circa 1922-1981 (Boxes 3-4 and OV 9; 1.1 linear feet)
Series 7: Artwork, circa 1918-1980 (Boxes 4-6 and OV 7-8, 10; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 8: Sketchbooks, circa 1918-1973 (Box 5; 5 folders)
Series 9: Photographs, circa 1914-1981 (Boxes 5-6; 0.6 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Weston, Edward,1886-1958 -- Photographs; Weston, Flora -- Photographs; United States. Aircraft Warning Service. Ground Observer Corps
Subjects-Topical:
Jewish artists; Painters -- California -- Los Angeles; Printmakers -- California -- Los Angeles; Sculptors -- California -- Los Angeles; Wood sculpture
Types of Materials:
Sound recordings; Sketchbooks; Photographs; Sketches; Diaries; Essays; Poems; Short stories; Notes; Transcripts; Prints
Names:
Blades, Harriet; Burton, Leslie; Budnick, Dan; Clements, Grace, 1905-1969; Cocker, Conrad; Danieli, Fidel; DeLuce, Robert; Drake, Alfred S.; Howe, Dudley; Krasnow, Rose, 1885-1984; Morley, Grace, 1900-; Noer, Philip; Owen, Dale; Owen, Elaine; Price, Aimée Brown, 1939-; Raboff, Ernest Lloyd; Raboff, Ina; Stone, Irving, 1903-; Weston, Edward, 1886-1958; Peter Krasnow Arts Foundation
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Materials, circa 1942-1983, Series 1:; (Boxes 1, 6; 7 folders)
  This series contains certificates and other materials from Rose Krasnow's service as a member of the Army Air Forces Ground Observer Corps; materials from memorial services, including the program and guest list from Peter Krasnow's memorial service; documentation of a project to publish Rose Krasnow's poetry; and a sound recording with commentary by Grace Clements on a Peter Krasnow exhibition. The recording is on 1 sound disc (lacquer).
  - Aircraft Warning Service, circa 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - In Memoriam ?? Isaac Berg Memorial Program, 1950 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Peter Krasnow Memorial Service, 1979 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ??Art in Our Time,?? a Commentary by Grace Clements, Side 1 ?? Art and Mental Health, Side 2 ?? Krasnow Exhibition, 1954 April 8 ?? May 5, (1 sound disc, Oversized material housed in Box 6, F1) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Poetry Project ?? Rose Krasnow, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Yahrzeit Notice ?? Goldie Levin, 1983 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ??Art in Our Time,?? a Commentary by Grace Clements, Side 1 ?? Art and Mental Health, Side 2 ?? Krasnow Exhibition, 1954 April 8 ?? May 5, (1 sound disc, Oversized material from Box 1, F4) (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, circa 1930-1984, Series 2:; (Box 1; 0.4 linear feet)
  This series contains the personal and professional correspondence of Peter and Rose Krasnow as well as a small amount of third party correspondence. Personal correspondence with friends and family involves health, work, daily events, and other life updates. Professional correspondence with art dealers, curators, gallery and museum directors, collectors, and colleges and universities deals with exhibitions, sales, loans, and donations of artwork. Correspondents include Leslie Burton and Harriet Blades, Dan Budnik, Grace Clements, Conrad Crocker, Dudley Howe, Lilly Weil Jaffe, Grace L. McCann Morley, Dale and Elaine Owen, Aimée Brown Price, Ernest and Ina Raboff, Irving Stone, and Edward Weston. Also included are scattered letters from Harry N. Abrams, B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundations, California Palace of the Legion of Honor, Arnold Chanin, John D. Entenza, Lorser Feitelson, Estelle Getz, Sadakichi Hartmann, Hilaire Hiler, Judah L. Magnes Memorial Museum, Jules Langsner, Long Beach Museum of Art, Los Angeles County Museum of Art, Los Angeles Hillel Council, Dorothy C. Miller, National Endowment for the Arts, National Portrait Gallery, Frances V. O'Connor, Peter and Rose Krasnow Foundation, Hilla Rebay, San Francisco Museum of Art, Abigail von Schlegell, and Whitney Museum of American Art.
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by surname of correspondent. Letters written by correspondents whose last name is unknown are filed alphabetically by first name of correspondent. Letters from unidentified correspondents are filed at the end of the series.
  - A, Miscellaneous, 1970 October 9 ?? 1977 June 27, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Aaron, Al (The Bowl of Hope)
    Abrams, Harry N. (See V - Vermont, Mildred B.)
    Akmakjian
    Armitage, Merle
  - B, Miscellaneous, 1935 April 2 -1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Baker, Katherine (San Francisco Museum of Art)
    Bender, Albert M.
    Berck, June
    Berg, Mr. and Mrs. Samuel
    Body, Manchester (Los Angeles Daily News)
    Bondi
  - B, Miscellaneous, 1945 August 16 - 1975 February 26 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Breslow, Marc (NBC Studios)
    Bruno, Virginia
    Buell (See Blades, Leslie Burton and Harriet)
    Byrnes, James B. (Los Angeles County Museum)
    Byron
  - Blades, Leslie Burton Blades and Harriet, 1944 January 22 - 1963 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Budnik, Dan, 1961 June 8 - 1972 August 6 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - C, Miscellaneous, 1934 January 25 - 1975 May 18, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Cabinet of the Minister of Education and Fine Arts, Paris
    Chanin, Arnold
    Charles
    Chodos, Israel (Sinai Temple)
    Clarke, Benjamin (Long Beach Museum of Art)
    Collett, Dorothy M. (University of Southern California)
    Cooper, Chuck
  - Clements, Grace, 1947-1958, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 13-15)
  - Crocker, Conrad, 1960 August 17 - 1970 July 4 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - D, Miscellaneous, 1937 October 7 - 1980 October 15, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Daniel
    David
    Claudia Davis (San Francisco Museum of Art)
    Robert DeLuce
    Dockum, Charles (See R - Rebay, Hilla)
    Dorothea and Leon
    Douglas
    Drake, Alfred
  - E, Miscellaneous, 1944 January 21 - 1966 November 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Ed and Dorothy
    Eggleston
    Eleanor
    Entenza, John D. (Arts and Architecture)
    Erika and Kem
    Eva
  - Ehrlich, Susan, 1978 January 25 - 1981 December 13 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - F, Miscellaneous, 1954 January 7 - 1975 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Feitelson, Lorser
    Fox, Alan C.
    Fox, Fred and Frieda (See also Price, Aimée Brown and R - Ratner, Joanne)
    Frances (See P - Phyllis)
    Franke, John
    Friedberg, Herman R. (See L - Lippert, David I.)
    Fry, Stephen M. (University of California, Riverside)
    Fulton, W. Joseph (Pasadena Art Institute)
  - G, Miscellaneous, 1934 February 27 - 1981 October 4, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Gaer, Joseph (Jewish Heritage Foundation)
    Geldman, Stephen
    Geoffrey
    George and Judy
    Getz, Estelle
    Gillman, Esther
    Goldstine, Regina
  - H, Miscellaneous, 1930 September 30 - 1971 March 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Hansen, Ejuar and Helga
    Hanson, Bertha A. (Glendale Art Association)
    Hartmann, Sadakichi
    Healy, Mark H.
    Helen
    Horad, M.
    Hesser, C.
  - H, Miscellaneous, 1943 March 15 - 1977 July 18, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Hiler, Hilaire
    Hirsh, Pauline (Jewish Federation Council)
    Historical Archives of Contemporary Art of the São Paulo Biennial
    Hoffman, Joseph (Judah L. Magnes Memorial Museum)
    Howe, Thomas C. (California Palace of the Legion of Honor)
    Hurwitz, Henry (The Menorah Journal)
  - Howe, Dudley, 1955 January 10 - 1971 September 30, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - J, Miscellaneous, 1950 May 2 - 1977 April 5, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Jacobs, Ferne
    Jacobsen, Alice S.
    James, Randi
    Jeanie and Sam
    Jeffers, Robinson
    Jenkins, Suzanne (National Portrait Gallery)
    Johnson, Thor (Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra)
    Joy
    Judy and Si
    June
  - Jaffe, Lilly Weil, 1962 January 22 - 1967 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - K, Miscellaneous, 1938 February 23 - 1975 May 31, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Kahn, Donald (Hillside Memorial Park and Mausoleum)
    Kandel, Aben
    Kandel, Stephen
    Kapin, Ruth and Sid
    Kazor, Virginia
    Kenyon, Gertrude (Life Magazine)
    Knapp, Marcia (Publishers' Weekly)
    Korbin, Keith
  - L, Miscellaneous, 1940 March 29 - 1984 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Langsner, Jules
    Laughton, Charles
    Leavitt, Thomas W. (Pasadena Art Museum)
    Leeper, John Palmer (Pasadena Art Institute)
    Lewenthal, Reeves (Associated American Artists, Inc.)
    Liebert, Eve
    Lindstrom, Charles (San Francisco Museum of Art)
    Lippert, David I. (Sinai Temple)
  - M, Miscellaneous, 1954 April 3 - 1981 January 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Sister Magdalen Mary
    Marian and Mac
    Marks, Albert E.
    Marks, Saul (The Plantin Press)
    McClellan, Douglas (Scripps College)
    McGehee, Ramiel
    McKinney, Eleanor
    Melchert, Jim (National Endowment for the Arts)
  - M, Miscellaneous, 1934 January 25 - 1979 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Mesnick, Charles (Westside Jewish Community Center)
    Milengen, Jeanne-Marie
    Miles, Ellen G. (National Portrait Gallery)
    Miller, Dorothy C. (Museum of Modern Art)
    Monzie, Anatole de
    Moran, Diane D.
    Moskowitz, Kenneth
    Moure, Nancy (Los Angeles County Museum of Art)
  - Morley, Grace L. McCann, 1937 September 16 - 1955 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - N, Miscellaneous, 1967 December 1 - 1982 August 23 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Nagel, Hede von
    Naomi
    Neumann, J.B. (See K - Kandel, Aben)
    Nikolashin, Natasha (Stanford University Libraries)
  - O, Miscellaneous, 1932 January 7 - 1964 June 5, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    O'Connor, Francis V.
    Otterström, Thomas
  - Owen, Dale and Elaine, 1965 August 3 - 1977 October 29, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - P, Miscellaneous, 1948 June 11 - 1976 January 12, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Pacht, Mr. and Mrs. Rudolph
    Pauloo, Sylvia
    Paxton
    Philip, Karen, and Michal
    Phyllis
    Pillsbury, Kent
  - P, Miscellaneous, 1939 June 1 - 1979 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Platt (See S - Selfman, Zena)
    Poland, Reginald (Fine Arts Gallery, City of San Diego)
    Pollack, Peter (see Clements, Grace)
    Popkin, Ruth
    Price, Monroe E. (University of California, Los Angeles)
  - Price, Aimée Brown, 1978 July 27 - 1981 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - R, Miscellaneous, 1942 September 26 - 1983 June 14, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Rabin, Henry (Los Angeles Hillel Council)
    Ratner, Joanne (Peter and Rose Krasnow Foundation)
    Reagan, Ronald and Nancy
    Rebay, Hilla
    Robert
    Ross, Marvin C. (Los Angeles County Museum)
    Roy, Jamini
  - Raboff, Ernest and Ina, 1965 April 16 - 1967 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - S, Miscellaneous, 1933 July 21 - 1976 January 12, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    San Francisco Museum of Art
    Schlegell, Abigail von (Pasadena Art Institute)
    Schneiderman
    Seewack, Lawrence B.
    Selfman, Zena (See also H - Hirsh, Pauline)
    Seman, Philip (See R - Rabin, Henry)
    Severe, Marc L. (American Consular Service)
    Sharkey, Alice M. (Whitney Museum of American Art)
    Sheldon, Ethel Farley (Sequoyah School)
  - S, Miscellaneous, 1930 March 21 - 1975 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Siegel, Yvonne
    Sieroty, Jean (Westside Jewish Community Center)
    Sklar, Dorothy (Westside Jewish Community Center)
    Sloane, William (Henry Holt and Company Publishers)
    Smith, Robert (See P - Price, Monroe E.)
    Smith, Steven
    Smolens, Ruth F. (B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundations)
    Spector
    Stanley
    Sternberg, Josef von
  - Stone, Irving, 1938 March 5 - 1954 January 23, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - T, Miscellaneous, 1953 February 26 - 1967 December 26 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Thompson, Merritt M.
    Traub, Lily Y.
    Tuchman (See Raboff, Ernest and Ina)
  - V, Miscellaneous, 1938 February 23 - 1970 October 26, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Varga, Margaret (Life Magazine)
    Vermont, Mildred B.
  - W, Miscellaneous, 1962 March 26 - 1972 December 7, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Willie, Bernice
    Wilson, Sherie, Gene, Jennifer, and Karen
    Winter, Ella (See K - Kandel, Aben)
    Wollemburg
    Wurdemann, Helen
  - Weston, Edward, 1933 November 28 - 1958 January 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Young, Bob, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Unidentified Correspondents, 1940 July 22 - 1961 November 28, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Writings and Notes, circa 1916-1980, Series 3:; (Boxes 1-2; 1.3 linear feet)
  This series contains writings and notes by Peter Krasnow, Rose Krasnow, and others. Writings by Peter Krasnow include a draft autobiography, essays, lectures on wood sculpture, typescripts, notes, and writings on art. Writings by Rose Krasnow include essays, plays, poetry, and short stories. Writings by others consist of essays, lectures, notes, plays, poetry, short stories, and typescripts. Other writers include Grace Clements, Fidel Danieli, Robert DeLuce, Alfred S. Drake, and Philip Noer.
  The series is arranged as 3 subseries:
  3.1: By Peter Krasnow, circa 1937-1980
  3.2: By Rose Krasnow, circa 1916-1979
  3.3: By Others, circa 1929-1980
  - By Peter Krasnow, circa 1937-1980, 3.1:
    - Autobiography - Draft, undated, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 49-52)
    - Autobiography - Typescript, circa 1970, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 53-56)
    - Autobiography - Edits by Susan Ehrlich, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Essay - "The Drawings," undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Essay - "Fame," undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Essay - "Miracles do Happen," 1975 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Lecture - Wood Sculpture, undated, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 61-64)
    - List - Works and Owners, undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Notes - Typewritten, circa 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Paper - Wood Sculpture, undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Projected Plan for Book of Pen-and-Ink Drawings, after 1946 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Typescripts - 10 Stories, undated, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
    - Typescript Manuscript - Unidentified, before 1970, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
    - Typescript - Unidentified, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Writings on Art, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - By Rose Krasnow, circa 1916-1979, 3.2:
    - Essay - "Religion: On Judaism," undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Notes, after 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Play - The Board Meeting, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Play - The Dreamer, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Play - Influence (Incomplete), undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Play - A Jewish Heart?with an Anti-Climax, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Play - A Paradox, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Play - Seder Night, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Play - The Story of Esther (Incomplete), undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Play - Tradition: An Allegory (Incomplete), undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Play - Yellow Peril (Incomplete), undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Poetry (Alphabetical by Title), 1916 January 18 - 1938, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Poetry - Untitled (Alphabetical by First Line), undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Poetry - "Lucinda," 1926 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Short Story - "Excelsior," undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Short Story - "French Leave," undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Short Story - "His Day Off," undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Short Story - "How the Mountain was Lost: A Fairy Tale without a Fairy," undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - By Others, circa 1929-1980, 3.3:
    - Essay - "Peter Krasnow: Pioneer Los Angeles Modernist," by Fidel Danieli, 1975 March 10 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Essay - Untitled, by Alfred S. Drake, after 1976 May (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Essay Introduction, by Franz Xaver Kappus, and Letters from Rainer Maria Rilke, 1929 June (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Essay - "To Give, One Must Have; To Teach, One Must Be," by Ethel Sheldon, circa 1960 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Essay - Krasnow--Sidebar to "Off-La Cienega," by Robert B. Young, circa 1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Essay - "Legend of the Painting," by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Essay on Peter Krasnow, by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)